Welcome to the soon to be time synchronisation section here, I'll describe the implementation and provide
some very brief background information about Simple Network Time Protocol and discuss the relevant ESP
RDF APIs as well.
So let's get right into the implementation.
Once the ESP 32 has a connection, meaning you've connected to an access point with an internet connection,
the S&P Tasks start function will be called the task start function will set off the free auto's time
synchronization task, which will call a function which obtains the updated time.
Also, I should mention that in this implementation, the task will keep synchronizing and checking
that the time is up to date.
Regarding the obtained time function, this function will initialize the same TV service to query Nesson
TBE server for the Universal Time.
Furthermore, the obtained time function will be initialized in case the time is not up to date.
The local time zone will be set once the SMTP service has been initialized.
The Web server will be alerted upon initialization and will respond with the updated time.
All right, so let's take a look at some additional information about Simple Network time protocol.
S&P or Simple Network Time Protocol is a protocol designed to synchronize the clock of devices connected
to the internet.
The basic operation is as follows The client, or ESP 32, connects to the server using the UDP protocol
on Port 123.
The client transmits the request packet to the server, then the server responds with the timestamp
packet.
The client can then pass out the current date and time values.
So in general, if the ESP 32 is connected to the internet, it can get the time and date using S&P.
Also, I should mention that S&P in the SPF is supported by lightweight IP functions.
Now, let's review how the SPF can help us with getting us up and running.
I suggest you review the A.P. documentation from Impressive.
You can find all of the relevant information here, as well as some of the functions we'll be using.
Also, I should mention that will set the time zone using the following functions here set in, we will
used to set the particular time zone and to set to initialize the time zone conversion routine.
More on this in a moment in the next slides.
All right, so some of this may not come together until we actually start writing the code.
But I think a quick review may help when we actually do that.
All right, so after the free autos task kicks off and the obtained time function is called, the Initialize
S.P. function is called for, the first SMTP function is used, which configures the client in pull
mode to query the server every seconds.
The function that accomplishes this is the soon to be set operating mode function using the step up
mode poll as the input parameter.
Also within the Initialise S.A. function, we'll tell the client which server to use a common choice
is a cluster of servers from pool that A.P. org will specify this in the function, S&P said.
Server name.
Then we'll initialize the service using S.P. Initialise once that's done, we can then set the time
zone variable and initialize the time zone conversion.
We'll set the time zone using the set EMV function, specifying Tzi for the time zone and your local
time zone string, and then call the time zone set function to initialize the time zone conversion routine.
After the service is initialized, we'll need to check if the system clock is updated, the time to
get the actual time from the system clock.
We'll use the time function, which updates the time type variable and to split the variable into different
time values such as year, month and day.
The local time underscore our function is used, which updates the team structure as shown in the image
here.
Well, then check the information from the team struck to see if the time was set.
Just like in the image shown below.
All right, so that's enough for now.
Let's get to coding in the next section.